hi everybody welcome back to the
channel today we're going to do
a coffee special thing in the Ninja
creamy nice easy recipe let's get to
it there's a new coffee van opened up in
my small town I normally go for coffee to
Cochrane Coffee Traders, it's a great it's a
great store, love the coffee, love the people,
it's really good quality but I thought I'd
try this new place that opened it's a van
so you know they kind of travel around the town um
it's a great idea and when we were there they were
just down the bottom of the road so we thought
we'd have a little meander down to the car park
(or the parking lot as as it may well be known)
um and see what was what so we grabbed a couple
of drinks and in the front they had some other
things that I wanted to try this is Araquipa..
I probably murdered that so apologies if I have.
So I grabbed this it's 150g of this and we also
had these which Cafecitas um they're little
coffee biscuits, cookies as they say over here,
so I thought we'd use these and make a super
simple coffee cookies and cream ice cream in
the Ninja creamy because there's not a lot of
this we're going to make just one single tub
of it and this is what you are going to need 150g
of Araquipa with coffee, one small pack which is
35g of cafecitas coffee cookies, you are going to
need 167g of 2% milk, 205g of 33% whipping cream,
39g of dextrose, 8g of salt and then we're good
to go why are we using dextrose in this and not
sugar but there's loads of sugar in this this is
I think 45% or 40% sugar so there's a lot of sugar
in that and to try and balance a really small
portion such as this is difficult if you were to
make a double batch so 1L or a even to a degree
a ninja creamy Deluxe with 750ml portion, it's
easier. It's much easier once you start balancing
recipes at 1 liter or 1 kilo but we are limited by
how much we can use here so if I were to use sugar
straight table sugar I can't get the balance right
I can't get the freezing point right because
there's then too much sugar too many solids too
much sugar but it doesn't bring the freezing
point up so the way to do that is to start
dealing with what's the most important part now
for me the freezing point is the most important
part not the amount of sugar in something now
generally they go hand in hand but that is not
always the case because if you add two much sugar
yes you will in start to increase the freezing
point but that's only relative to the sugar once
you start adding all the other ingredients like
skin milk powder cream you know if you're using
different sugars dextrose, Erythritol, Xylitol,
Allulose so many different things they all start
to change that freezing point so when you look at
a recipe it's about the amount of fat doesn't
really make any difference anywhere from kind
of 5% up to Glorious 22% UK fatty ice cream you
can do anything in that in that range that's fine
sugar content it's kind of subjective because some
people like sugar content down into like the the
12% range um that's really low and you start to
lack solids in ice cream and the freezing point
ends up too low gelata has much higher amounts of
sugar because it's much lower in fat than standard
American ice cream so gelata can have kind of
right the way up to 22% sugar but it balances out
right you don't think it's super sweet because
how the recipe is milk solid is nonfat you can
go down to 5% which is where we are in this
uh this will be a good chunk of milk solids
nonfat milk solids nonfat it just means that we
want the milk proteins to make Luxury Ice Cream
it's super important to create a smooth mouth
feel and texture if we don't have milk solids
or milk proteins then we're looking at plant-based
recipes and that actually is the hardest part part
of a plant-based recipe is to get that mouth feel
by adding something in equivalency to milk protein
and this is where inulin comes in generally um
but you can use like multitexture as well but well
that's a thing for a different video um finally
we're looking at total solids this is kind of
where we start to balance out recipes with sugar
we want to be somewhere around late 30s early 40s
you can go up to mid-40s perent that is and then
water content you know somewhere between the the
late 40s to early 60s percent water content so in
this tub which I it's 550g by the time it comes
up to that line we got 61% water we have 38%
solids we have 5% milk solids nonfat we have
18% sugar but this is dexos so this is dextrose
combined with the sugar in here combined with the
sugar lactose in our milk and cream and we have
13.3% fat so fat content is great sugar content
is fine because we're using dextrose which is
nowhere near as sweet as standard table sugar
but it really hits that freezing point nicely I
like to use cold process stabilizers for Ninja
creami it's just easy but we need to get this
mixed up so we're going to get a bowl and get
all our ingredients in there nice clean Bowl get
rid of that here we go first thing we're going to
weigh.... weigh your stuff
right 205g of whipping cream
204... don't make me open another one
.....205 I mean you couldn't make that
up 205g of our whipping cream it wouldn't make
any difference 203 202 don't worry about it 167g
of "stupid to pour" milk. If you don't have
dextrose can you use sugar? at a pinch yes
you could use sugar the the one absolute
saving grace to the ninja creami is it can
decimate things down to you know whatever
but with a serving temperature of -13°C,
it will go hard again if you put it back in the
freezer..... hard, so you have to spin it again
if you use dextrose it won't go hard super hard
when you put it back in the freezer you can just
take it out and eat it which is how I make all my
ice creams. Dextrose 38.. 39g we're going to use
pink Himalayan salt just because we can this
is 0.8g I don't know, not wearing it out....
something like that and then really all we
need to do is add this so stabilizer. Yeah
I'm going to use Guar gum, super dark color
that's 100% the uh right first things first
definitely part of the Dulce de leche family which
is never a bad thing I did an incredible Dulce de
Leche recipe months ago now from a friend that
lives down in Mexico originally from Argentina,
anyway we're going to put all of that in there
we need all of this so don't leave any on the
spoon don't leave any in the tub let's get that
all in here because I really want to lick that
spoon right pop in the microwave we're going
to pop this in the microwave just to warm it
up a little bit we don't want to go
too mad so something like 30 seconds.
That's 30 seconds we're not super heating this
but we want to heat it enough so that that add
a k again apologies blends into our dairy needs
just a little bit more heat so that heat again
is just to get that araquipa dissolved into our
liquid it's there now it's dissolved you might
find a couple of tiny little bits blended back
in doesn't matter uh finally we are just going
to add our Guar gum so I'm going to take one
teaspoon of sugar, one eighth of a teaspoon
of Guar gum mix it up that is the purpose
of the sugar make sure there's no lumps in
your powder add that in there one teaspoon of
sugar will make no difference to the recipe
whatsoever right that in there
let's get it in our ninja creami tub
perfect... lid on in the freezer it
goes
It's actually been like, I don't know, a
week since I've prepared this let's get it in
[Music]
see how it's getting
on don't think it needs
anymore let's get this [Music]
out all right so the first thing to
know is these little coffee biscuits
probably Cafecitas I'm terrible at pronunciation
they smell quite nice, they smell like coffee
cake old fashioned coffee and walnut cake.
They're nice they'd work for a cookies and cream
in this so says product of Colombia on the back
it would make sense as a Colombian Coffee
Company... let's try a proper
size portion of the ice cream
Super smooth you know exactly what you'd expect
from the channel flavor it's a hybrid flavor
between you know dula dele and coffee it it's a
nice coffee flavor it is a nice coffee flavor it's
a really unique kind of combination I've never
had this like caramel coffee combo before and I
like it yeah really tasty for coffee ice cream
it's not got strong enough flavor for caramel
ice cream it's not got enough flavor for Coffee
caramel ice cream it works because you don't want
either one to overpower but you could probably
make this with standard dulce de leche and some
instant coffee powder if you wanted to adjust
then you can heat up your ingredients and steep
coffee beans you know that kind of thing in there
that will give you a very similar flavor as well.
Delicious really nice and I'm I'm really glad
that we popped down the road and bought some
coffee to get these I mean we didn't buy the
coffee to get these ingredients but they were
there staring at me in the face and I thought
I'm going to make some ice cream out that so
uh a nice new product to try and make ice cream
and or gelato out of depending on what recipe you
use thanks so much for watching don't forget to
like and subscribe and I will see you next time
[Music]